HAOMIN CHEN

Google Scholar: https://www.linkedin.com/in/haomin-chen-jhu-cs/

Personal website: https://haomin-website.netlify.app/

263 Congressional Lane, Rockville, Maryland, 20852 (open to relocate)

(443) · 630 · 2698 ♦ haominchen1234@gmail.com ♦ Google Scholar

SUMMARY

Applied Research Scientist working in Ericsson LynkAI for interpretable video translation. Graduated as a Computer Science Ph.D. from Johns Hopkins University with a background in interpretable computer vision systems for medical image analysis. Rich experience with computer vision, generative AI and human-computer interaction. The first author of Nature partner journal paper. Excellent communication skills and ability to work on multi-disciplinary teams.

EDUCATIONS

Johns Hopkins University

Jan 2018 - Dec 2022 (Degree Completed)

Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science

Degree Awarded in May 2023

Advisors: Dr. Mathias Unberath, Dr. Gregory Hager

Baltimore, MD, USA

First author publications: 5 conference papers, 4 journal papers

First author of one Nature partner journal paper

Columbia University

Sep 2016 - Dec 2017

Master of Arts, Statistics Overall GPA: 4.1 / 4.0 New York City, NY, USA

Fudan University

Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

Bachelor of Science, Physics

Shanghai, CHINA

Core GPA: 3.6 / 4.0

SKILLS

Python, C++, Linux, Slurm, Docker, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Matlab, R, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Medical Image Analysis, Human-Computer Interaction, Interpretable Learning, Classification, Object Detection, Instance Segmentation, LLM, Generative AI, Audio Processing, Statistical Analysis

EXPERIENCES

Ericsson, Los Angeles

Feb 2023 - now

Applied Research Scientist

Los Angeles, CA, USA

Video Translation with Lip Sync and Preserving Tone by Generative AI

- · Created the largest dataset of talking head videos from YouTube with 13 languages & 600 hours.
- · Established multi-person & lingual audio/video synchronization, outperforming ElevenLabs.
- · Refined the facial landmark generation network for better articulation.
- · Used diffusion to achieve immersive lip synchronization in videos with translated audio.

Meta, Redmond

Jun 2022 - Oct 2022

Redmond, WA, USA

Research Intern

2D-3D Style Transfer for VR

- · Achieved real-time inference and human interaction for personalized customization.
- · Preserved 3D visual reality and outperformed other methods in user experience.

- · Stylized 3D scene with 2D style images by differential rendering.
- · Learned quickly style transfer, 3D graphics, and rendering from scratch in one week.
- · Exceeded director/mentor/peers' expectations in internship review.

PingAn Technology, Bethesda

May 2019 - Dec 2019

Applied Research Intern

Bethesda, MD, USA

Fracture Detection in Pelvic Trauma X-rays

- · Deployed in Chang Gung Memorial Hospital in Taiwan and used by over 5000 patients.
- · First-author conference paper is accepted by ECCV 2020 with a poster presentation.
- · Improved detection AUC from 0.95 to 0.98 and fracture recall from 0.89 to 0.93 (FPR=0.1).
- · Mimicked radiologists to detect fractures by comparing bilateral symmetric regions.
- · Focused on anatomical asymmetry with contrastive learning.

NVIDIA, Bethesda

May 2018 - Dec 2018

Applied Research Intern

Bethesda, MD, USA

Multi-Abnormality Classification in Chest X-rays

- · First-author conference paper is accepted by MIDL 2019 with an oral presentation.
- · First-author journal paper is accepted by Medical Image Analysis (IF = 13.8).
- · Improved classification AUC from 0.87 to 0.89.
- · Robust to incompletely labelled data and preserved 85% performance drop.
- · Mimicked radiologists to classify abnormality with clinical taxonomy.
- · Established numerically stable method for calculation of CE loss of unconditional probabilities.

PingAn Technology, Shanghai

May 2017 - Aug 2017

Data Mining Scientist Intern

Shanghai, CHINA

Lung Nodule Detection in CT Scans

- · Achieved top 6 out of 2887 teams in the Skylake competition by Intel and Alibaba.
- · Applied 3D UNet with Pytorch & Faster RCNN with Caffe for detection in 1000 CT scans.
- · Utilized fusion methods to make models more robust and generalizable.

Johns Hopkins University

Jan 2018 - Feb 2023

Research Assistant

Baltimore, MD, USA

Systematic Review for Interpretable ML in Medical Image Analysis

- · First-author journal paper is accepted in npj Digital Medicine (IF = 11.6).
- · Proposed interpretability as a relationship between end users instead of as a property of models.
- · Introduced guidelines to recommend first understanding end users before model design.
- · Conducted a systematic review in PubMed, EMBASE and Compendex databases.
- · Identified 2508 records and included 68 articles.

Interpretable Cancer Subtyping with Cytopathology Images

- · First-author conference paper is accepted in ICML workshop.
- · Improved cancer subtyping AUC from 0.75 to 0.87 and provided interpretation.
- · Analyzed cell composition by cell segmentation deep features and rule-based learning.
- · Proved to be interpretable in a web-based user study with pathologists.

Interpretable High-Quality ROI Extraction with Cytopathology Images

- · First-author conference paper is accepted in MICCAI workshop.
- · Created automatic and interactive high-quality ROI extraction with deep clustering.
- \cdot Improved recall from 11% to 51% and speeded up by 10 times.

Pelvic Fracture Severity Grading with CT Scans

- · First-author journal paper under third-round review in IEEE TMI (IF = 10.6).
- · Applied Bayesian model to predict severity grading with AO/OTA clinical grading criterion.
- · Proposed Bayesian refinement to retrieve false negative fractures.
- · Established augmented inference to calculate robust fracture confidence scores.

Automatic Splenic Injury Grading System with CT Scans

- · First-author journal paper is accepted in Emergency Radiology (IF = 1.59).
- · Proposed neuralsymbolic learning by following AAST clinical guideline.
- · Created rule-based symbolic reasoning for severity grading with deep network findings.

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Journal papers:

- 1. **Haomin Chen***, Catalina Gomez*, Chien-Ming Huang, Mathias Unberath. Explainable Medical Imaging AI Needs Human-Centered Design: Guidelines and Evidence from a Systematic Review. (2022) npj Digital Medicine (IF=11.65) 5, 156.
- 2. *Haomin Chen*, Shun Miao, Daguang Xu, Gregory Hager, Adam Harrison. Deep hierarchical multi-label classification applied to chest X-ray abnormality taxonomies. (2020) **Medical Image Analysis (IF=13.82) 66**, 101811.
- 3. T. Y. Alvin Liu*, *Haomin Chen**, Catalina Gomez, Zelia Correa, Mathias Unberath. Direct Gene Expression Profile Prediction for Uveal Melanoma from Digital Cytopathology Images via Deep Learning. (2022) **Ophthalmology Science (IF=7.18)** 100240.
- 4. *Haomin Chen*, David Dreizin, Mathias Unberath. Toward automated interpretable AAST grading for blunt splenic injury. (2022) **Emergency Radiology (IF=1.59)**
- 5. David Dreizin, Bryan Nixon, Jiazhen Hu, Benjamin Albert, Chang Yan, Gary Yang, *Haomin Chen*, Yuanyuan Liang, Nahye Kim, Jean Jeudy, Guang Li, Elana B. Smith, Mathias Unberath. A pilot study of deep learning-based CT volumetry for traumatic hemothorax. (2022) Emergency Radiology (IF=1.59) DOI:10.1007/s10140-022-02087-5.

Conference papers:

- 1. **Haomin Chen***, Yirui Wang*, Kang Zheng, Weijian Li, Chi-Tung Chang, Adam P. Harrison, Jing Xiao, Gregory D. Hager, Le Lu, Chien-Hung Liao, Shun Miao. Anatomy-aware siamese network: Exploiting semantic asymmetry for accurate pelvic fracture detection in x-ray images. **ECCV** 2020.
- 2. *Haomin Chen*, Shun Miao, Daguang Xu, Gregory D. Hager, Adam P. Harrison. Deep hierarchical multi-label classification of chest X-ray images. **MIDL** 2019.
- 3. *Haomin Chen*, T. Y. Alvin Liu, Catalina, Gomez, Mathias Unberath. An Interpretable Algorithm for Uveal Melanoma Subtyping from Whole Slide Cytology Images. *IMLH*, 2021. (*ICML workshop*).
- 4. *Haomin Chen*, T. Y. Alvin Liu, Zelia M. Correa, Mathias Unberath. An Interactive Approach to Region of Interest Selection in Cytologic Analysis of Uveal Melanoma Based on Unsupervised Clustering. **OMIA**, 2020 (MICCAI workshop).
- 5. David Dreizin, *Haomin Chen*, Alexander Upegui, Guang Li, Mathias Unberath. Blunt splenic trauma: accuracy of automated active bleed and contained vascular injury detection on CT with Faster R-CNN. **ASER** 2022 and **RSNA** 2022.

- David Dreizin, *Haomin Chen*, Alexander Upegui, Guang Li, Mathias Unberath. Blunt splenic trauma: automated splenic parenchymal disruption volumes for decision making in patients with no vascular injuries on CT. ASER 2022 and RSNA 2022.
- 7. Yifan Gao*, *Haomin Chen**, Catalina Gomez*, Sophie Cai, Craig K. Jones, Adrienne Scott, Mathias Unberath. An Interpretable Approach to Identifying Sea Fan Neovascularization in Ultra-Widefield Color Fundus Photographs of Patients With Sickle Cell Hemoglobinopathy. **SPIE**, 2021.
- 8. T. Y. Alvin Liu, Hongxi Zhu, *Haomin Chen*, J. Fernando Arevalo, Ferdinand K. Hui, Paul H. Yi, Jinchi Wei, Mathias Unberath, Zelia M. Correa. Gene Expression Profile Prediction in Uveal Melanoma Using Deep Learning: A Pilot Study for the Development of an Alternative Survival Prediction Tool. **Ophthalmology Retina**, 2020.

AWARDS

Mentor award in the Howard County Public School.	April 2022
National College Students Mathematics Competition, National Silver Medal.	Oct 2013
National College Students Mathematics Model Contest, the third prize of Shanghai.	Oct 2014
Second-class scholarship of Fudan University.	May~2015
Mensa Member in China.	May 2016